Hello everyone, you all are very welcome.
You're watching You the Year.  I am
your personal advisor Amit Raj Sharma.
In today's video we will learn
about Future Perfect Plan of ICICI Prudential Life Insurance Company Limited.
This plan is a participating
non-linked individual savings life
insurance plan.  Understand in simple words.  The
premium that we pay to the company here
, the company will not invest it in the market i.e.
in equity or stocks,
hence there will be no market related risk.
As a result, if the company announces the bonus rate at the end of the financial year, the
plan will continue to
accumulate the same which we will get on
maturity along with guaranteed maturity benefit.  Along with
this,
we will have life insurance during the policy term
because this is a life insurance policy.   If
something happens to us, that benefit will be given to the nominee.  We will
understand further how it is beneficial.  Now please turn the video
on full screen so that we can understand the
eligibility criteria of ICICI Pro Future Perfect Plan.
If you
take a premium payment term of 5 years, then you will
get a form of 10 to 15 years along with it and the
age limit for taking this option is
from 3 years to 45 years in which you have a
maturity age of 18 to 60 years, that is, you
can remain under the cover for a minimum of 18 years and a maximum of 60 years.
If you
take a premium payment term of 10 years, then you will get a positive of 15 to 20
years and
for taking this option, the age limit has been kept from a child of 91 days to
persons of 55 years.  The
maturity age limit has been
kept from 18 to 70 years.  In this way,
this detail is given here.
With all the options, there is a minimum annual premium limit of ₹00
and if you pay the annual premium 10 times, it will reach
₹1 lakh.  That will be
some assured here which you
will call life cover.  The plan offers tax benefits
for premiums under section 10D
and tax-free benefits under section 10D.
AP stands for
Annualized Premium.  Only if your
annual premium is up to ₹5 lakh.
Let us now know about the benefits of ICICI Pharma Life
's Future Perfect Plan.
Some benefits in this plan
are guaranteed and some depend on bonuses.
What will be the guaranteed benefit? The benefit that will be
received at maturity will be the guaranteed
maturity benefit.
Accrued Guaranteed Additions
and Vestiges accruing during the policy term Simple Reversionary Bonus and
Terminal Bonus if announced by the company.
Right?  The question here is
what is Guaranteed Maturity Benefit
?  So Guaranteed Maturity Benefit is a
lump sum amount that you will receive on maturity
at the end of the policy term
which you decide at the time of purchasing the plan and is
decided on the basis of your age, policy term, premium payment term and gender.  That
means, while taking the plan, you will
pay the premium based on the amount you decide and you will
get it as a guaranteed maturity benefit.  During the policy term, you
get guaranteed additions which are
a fixed percentage of your annual premium.   For the
first 5 years of the policy, if your premium
payment term is 5 years or 7 years, then
8% of the annual premium will keep getting added every year.
If the premium payment term in your policy is 10 years, 15 years
or 20 years, then for the
first 5 years 10% of your annual premium is
fine. Similarly, for the next 5 years i.e. 6 to
10 years, if the premium payment term is
less than 10 years, then 10%. If the premium payment term is
10 years or more, then
12% of the annual premium will keep getting added. Then for the next 5 years i.e.
11 to 15 years, if the premium payment term is
less than 10 years, then 12% of the annual premium will keep getting
added.  If the premium payment term is
10 years or more, then 15%,
after that 15% in the next 5 years, if the
premium payment term is less than 10 years, that is,
5 years and 7 years, if the
premium payment term is 10 years, 15 years or 20
years, then 18% of the annual base premium will be
yours. The
Vestige Simple Reversionary Bonus added to the Guaranteed Addition Policy, that is,
whatever amount of Simple Reversionary Bonus is
announced, we
call that amount Vestige Simple Reversionary Bonus,
which
you withdraw by multiplying it by a certain percentage of the policy term.  The
terminal bonus can be a fixed
amount.  If at the
end of the policy i.e. at the end of the policy term, the
company announces the bonus date terminal bonus
rate, then only a
certain percentage of this sum will be given.  What does A mean if the policyholder
dies during the policy term
?  Sum Assured
on Death plus any bonus such as Simple
Reversionary Bonus or Terminal Bonus.
After that the Accrued Guarantee Edition will be
compared.  B Equal To means that
whatever premium has been paid till
the date of death, 105% of it will be deducted and
whichever is higher of the two will be
given to the nominee as a death benefit and the
policy will be closed.  Sum Assured on Death
means either
10 times your annual premium or your
guaranteed maturity benefit.
Whichever is higher of the two will be the sum on death which will be
payable to your nominee along with the death benefit as death
benefit. Now
an example has been given here in the policy brochure on
their website, considering it,
age 35 years, positerm of 20 years,
premium payment of 10 years, we have chosen annual mode
for premium payment, we are paying a premium of ₹000 annually,
so the sum on
death has been taken as ₹3000 in the policy brochure,
so we are considering the same, the
total premium paid will be ₹3 lakh, so the
guaranteed maturity benefit amount is
₹270348.
This is the amount on which the bonus will be
calculated.  Guaranteed addition and
maturity payout will be ₹82500.
This is fixed.  Rest
of the bonus rates are being told as per the rates mentioned here.
If the rate of return is 4%
then ₹3827 can become
₹151532 if it is 8%.
And the estimated terminal
bonus is being said to be ₹7854.
If the rate of return is 4% or
8%, then it is being reported as ₹2782.  That means,
if the rate of return is 4%, the
estimated maturity
benefit will be ₹434729.
If the rate of return is 8%, then the amount can be Rs 71463 by adding guaranteed
benefit and non-guaranteed i.e. guaranteed
benefit along with bonus.
Here the
guaranteed maturity benefit is ₹270348 on
which we can calculate the bonus.
Ok?  So how did the guaranteed addition
amount come to be so high?  So look
what we have here for 10 years?  Premium
payment term.  So for the first 5 years, we will withdraw
10% of our annual premium i.e. 10% of ₹00.  If we
multiply it by five, it will become
15,000 because this much was collected in the first 5
years.  What will happen in the next 5 years
?  If we take out 12% of the annual premium of ₹00 and
multiply it by five, then
₹18,000 will be collected.  Ok?  Then for the next
5 years, we will withdraw 15% of the annual premium of ₹00 and
multiply it by five because
what is accumulating from 11 to 15, that is,
what is accumulating in five years will
come to an amount which is ₹22,500.  Then
we will take out 18% of ₹00 and multiply it by five again.
So here the
amount will come to ₹27,000.  In this way, if you
add the entire amount here, the
amount of Accrued Guaranteed Addition will come to ₹82,500.
Now the rate of simple reversionary bonus
on their website is 2.5%.  So
what are we doing?
We are taking out 2.5% of 270348 and multiplying it by 20.
So the total sum of Simple Reversionary
Bonus or say Vestage Simple Reversionary
Bonus came to ₹135174.  This is
the website on which
bonus rates are available.  The deduction on that is
₹3,000 which was taken in the policy term.
Now let us assume that the policyholder
dies after completion of 10 years of the policy.
So, the
amount of guaranteed addition that will be earned within 10 years will be
₹33,000.  Now we will take out the
vested simple reversal bonus here.
That is, if we subtract 2.5% of our Guaranteed Sum Maturity
or Guaranteed Maturity Benefit of
₹70348 and
multiply it by 10, then the
amount will become ₹67587, that is, the nominee will get
Sum on Death of ₹33000, Guaranteed Addition of ₹33000,
Vest Simple Event Bonus of ₹67587 and Terminal
Bonus, if any, and the policy will be
closed.  We could not find the terminal bonus rate
on their website.  Because of this we are
unable to tell.  You can also see
that the pay rate of
Simple Reversal Bonus given here for Future Perfect is 2.5%
and that of Volume Three is 2.25%.
So let's assume the higher side
here is 2.5%.  We have done the
calculation from that here.  Rest of the
PDF of this, you will get it on the Telegram channel.  Along with that
I have given the link
in the reference section of the video.
You can take it from there also.  If you
want any other information related to this plan,
you can ask in the comment section.
I will get a separate video and
tell you in that.
Thank you very much for patiently watching the video till the end.
Thanks a bundle.  Understand one thing yourself.
Explain to others that insurance is a
protection.  Never take incomplete protection.
Please like and
share the video.  Please subscribe to the channel and
turn on all notification bells.  Thank you.   Take
care of yourself.